#### Contact

erwindt@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/erwin-d-tangonan-msn-rn-bshs-ccrn-crni-b3120239 (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Nursing

**Critical Care** 

ICU

## Languages

Tagalog

Ilocano

**English** 

### Certifications

**CCRN** 

CRNI

#### Honors-Awards

Sigma Theta Tau International

#### **Patents**

Vascular Access Specialist

# Erwin D. Tangonan MSN, RN, BSHS, CCRN, CRNI

Venous Access Nurse at NYU Langone Hospital—Brooklyn Ridgewood, New York

## Summary

A Registered Nurse in the State of New York for 12 yrs with strong Critical-Care experience, an active member and ambassador to the American Association of Critical-Care Nurses (AACN), Infusion Nurses Society (INS), and the Association for Vascular Access (AVA). Currently certified in CCRN and CRNI. Work as a PICC nurse for a 350+ community, private, non-profit, teaching hospital, inserting 2-7 PICCs/day or 200+/yr; or 5-10 Midlines. Also work in Interventional Radiology (IR) and proficient with moderate sedation. Help develop and organize institutional policies/procedures to help guide nursing-practice. I seek ways to better and challenge myself, and always up for new challenges.

## Experience

NYU Langone Hospital—Brooklyn Venous Access Nurse March 2020 - Present (5 months) Brooklyn, New York, United States

Part of the Venous Access Team at NYULH-Brooklyn. Inserts/Troubleshoots PICCs (Arrow) and Midlines (PowerWand XL). Activates Chemoports/ Mediports, and often places PIVs for patients whom staffs have difficulty gaining venous accesses. Familiar with VasoNova Vascular Positioning System in utilizing PICC insertion.

Wyckoff Heights Medical Center 13 years

Vascular Access Nurse Specialist (IV/PICC-Line Nurse) April 2015 - Present (5 years 4 months) Greater New York City Area

- Work independently and proficiently in PICC and Midline insertions, as well as other vascular access devices within my scope of practice.
- Familiar with AccuCATHs and MidLine catheter insertions.

- Certified PICC inserter from BARD Access Inc.
- Develop Policy/Procedures regarding Vascular Access.
- Collaborate with interdisciplinary teams to improve patient care outcomes (e.g. lenth of stay, improve inpatient recovery, and the prevention of CLABSI).
- Educate nurses, doctors, and families regarding PICC maintenance, and other VADs.
- Current member of INS and AVA.
- CRNI Certified
- VA-BC certification in progress.

## Interventional Radiology Nurse August 2015 - Present (5 years) Brooklyn

- Assisted patients in preparation for various IR procedures, such as angiograms, embolizations, chemo-embolizations, insertions of various drainage, placements of long-term catheters (e.g. Chemoports/Mediports, Hickman, PICC lines, and other tunneled/nontunneled catheters) and various biopsies.
- Provided moderate sedation to patient undergoing interventional radiologic procedures.
- Comfortable in managing critically-ill patients.
- Familiar with various drains, catheters, and wires used in IR.
- Well organized and excellent patient care skills.

## Critical Care Registered Nurse April 2008 - April 2015 (7 years 1 month) Brooklyn

- Cared for critically-ill patients in a 16-bed, combined MICU/CCU.
- AACN Ambassador and CCRN certified.
- Worked in Post-Anesthesia Care Unit/Recovery Unit (PACU), Emergency Department (ED), Endoscopy, Surgical Step-down, Telemetry, and other Med/Surg floors.
- Oriented new ICU staffs, and other nurses cross-training from ED and PACU.
- Encouraged several nurses in pursuant of a nursing certification (e.g, PCCN, CCRN, CMSRN, etc.).
- Worked in Interventional Radiology department.

## Telemetry/Step-Down August 2007 - August 2009 (2 years 1 month) Brooklyn, NY

- Very busy 50+ bed telemetry unit with 4 bed Stepdown.

- Care for 6-9 telemetry patients with mulitple cardiac problems.
- Cross-trained to CCU/MICU.
- Floated to Emergency Room, PACU, and CCU/MICU.
- Collaborated with interdisciplinary teams to facilitate patient discharges.

## Bellevue Healthcare Critical Care Registered Nurse April 2013 - December 2013 (9 months) New York, New York

- Worked in CCU, and often floated to MICU, SICU, and Neuro-ICU.
- Cared for critically-ill patients on vents with mulitple drips.
- Assisted staffs in preparation of Abiomed Impella machines.
- Cared for patients under hypothermia treatment, patient with pericardial drains, multiple chest-tubes, and patients with Swan-Ganz, and othe hemodynamic monitoring devices.
- Obtain values from a Swan-Ganz catheter (e.g. wedging pulmonary artery catheter).
- Employed as a Perdiem RN by TPF Nursing Agency in Greenwich Village, NY, NY.

NewYork-Presbyterian Hospital Staff Registered Nurse August 2010 - August 2012 (2 years 1 month) New York, New York

Floated primarily in 5G-North/South and 5H-North.

## Saint Vincent Catholic Medical Centres of New York Registered Nurse

August 2007 - January 2010 (2 years 6 months)

New York, NY

- Floated to various units, such as ED, Telemetry, Oncology, Orthopedic, MICU/CCU, and HIV unit.
- Managed patients in the ICU with multiple vasoactive and sedation drips.
- Was hired as a full-time staff to the CTICU prior to closing of the hospital in early 2010.
- Assisted in infusion of chemotherapy on Oncology unit.
- Set-up Continuous Passive Motion (CPM) machine after a patient undergone total knee replacement surgery on Ortho unit.
- Employed as a Perdiem RN by TPF Nursing Agency in Greenwich Village, NY, NY.

Mount Sinai Health System Staff Registered Nurse March 2007 - July 2007 (5 months) New York, New York

Was a full-time staff in 9-West, a unit composed of a Step-Down, Ventilator, and Telemetry.

## Education

Jacksonville University

Master's degree, Nursing Administration · (2017 - 2018)

State University of New York Downstate Medical Center College of Medicine

Bachelor of Nursing, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2005 - 2006)

Stony Brook University

Bachelor of Health Science, Emergency Preparedness · (2001 - 2004)